Guide to the Robert Frost at Stanford Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Robert Frost at Stanford collection
1936-1958
SC1229
0.25 Linear feet
Ephemera documenting Robert Frost, his work and visits to Stanford.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of collected ephemera documenting Robert Frost, his work and visits to Stanford.
Access Terms
Frost, Robert, 1874-1963.; American poetry--20th century.; Poetry.; Poets, American--20th century.
Collection Contents
- Ephemera, 1936-1958
  - 1.) Birches: Bread Loaf School of English -French fold pamphlet from a single sheet of paper. This was the first separate printing of one of Frost's most famous poems. 2nd printing thus on green laid paper. Scarce. (Box 1)
  - 2.) Robert Frost: Godfather of Bread Loaf: Bread Load School of English -small 6 page staple-bound pamphlet with a woodcut illustration on the front cover. This pamphlet discusses the history of the Bread Loaf School of English, and the Bread Loaf Writer's conference, along with details of Robert Frost's co-founding of the school and his contributions to both the school and the conference. (Box 1)
  - 3.) Handwritten Postcard from Louis Mertins (primary bibliographer of Robert Frost) to collector regarding a possible meeting. Signed by Mertins. (Box 1)
  - 4.) Christmas Card with printed signature of Esther & Louis Mertins. Includes the mailing envelope hand addressed by Mertins. (Box 1)
  - 5.) Typed postcard from Louis Mertins (with author's imprinted name at the top) to the collector, with information about his upcoming meeting with Lord Dunsany. Includes handwritten author initials. Also included is a newspaper clipping regarding Lord Dunsany (Box 1)
  - 6.) Thursday, August 17th, 1950issueof The ManchesterGuardian Weekly (Manchester UK), which includes the article: Robert Frost in England by Louis Mertins which includes a small handwritten inscription by the author, signed. (Box 1)
  - 7.) Sunday, June 7,1936 issue of the New York Herald Tribune (section VII, pages 3-4) which features the book review of A Further Range by Robert Frost which includes a large black and white photograph of the author, signed by Robert Frost. (Box 1)
  - 8.) Envelope from the Libraryof Congress and a certificate of Registration of a Claim to Copyright in a photograph. Accompanied by a black and white 4"x6" photograph of Robert Frost -regarding a photo that the previous owner took of Frost during Frost's lecture tour to Stanford University May 5 (Box 1)
  - 9.) Envelope from the California Friends of Robert Frost with a typewritten letter from G. William Gahagan Executive Secretary (it's a donor request letter) to which is added a handwritten note asking the collector to present the letter to the Ina Coolbrith Circle group. Signed. (Box 1)
  - 10.) Envelopefrom the California Friends of Robert Frost with a typewritten letter (dated April 16,1964) noting condolences that the collector was not able to attend the Robert Frost Commemorative Luncheon. Hand-signed by the author. Laid-in is a re-order envelope with negatives of photographs of Robert Frost (possibly at the Stanford University reading mentioned in the LOC certificate) along with a ticket to the California Friends of the Library luncheon on March 26,1964 and two handwritten notes by the collector. (Box 1)
  - 11.) Address label attached to brown paper (the top portion of a package that was sent to the collector) from Lawrance Thompson (a biographer of Robert Frost). The collector's address is typed; the return address from Thompson is handwritten. Includes a duplicate of the original letter sent by the collector to Thompson. (Box 1)
  - 12.) Address label attached to brown paper (the top portion of a package that was sent to the collector) from Reginald Cook (a critic of Robert Frost). The collector's address is typed; the return address from Cook is handwritten, includes a duplicate of the original letter sent by the collector to Cook. (Box 1)
  - 13.) Flyer for: "An Evening with Robert Frost11 sponsored by Princeton Alumni Association for May 29th, 1956which includes a handwritten note from Joyce Lobner (unsure of association). (Box 1)
  - 14.) Handwritten letter from the author Robert Hillyer (biographer of Robert Frost) dated 9, April 1954 to collector regarding the search for an elusive title by the author (A Letter to Robert Frost), hand signed. Includes an envelope handwritten by the author. (Box 1)
  - 15.) Brown paper (the top portion of a package that was sent to the collector) from Robert Frost. Both return address and package address are handwritten by Frost. (Box 1)
  - 16.) Broadside publicizing a reading by Robert Frost atStanford University, Monday, May 5th, 1958 at the Memorial Hall. Thiscopy includesthe handwritten initialsof Robert Frost. (Box 1)
  - 17.) Offprint from American Literature (Vol. 19, No.4, January 1948) by Reginald L.Cook: Robert Frost's Asides on his Poetry. (Box 1)
  - 18.) Middlebury College Bulletin April, 1958: Bread Loaf Writer's Conference which describes the 33rd Annual Session of the Bread Loaf Writer's Conference. Robert Frost is one of the special Lecturers. (Box 1)
  - 19.) Middlebury College Publication: Robert Frost. 1954. This is copy number 47 (of an unknown limitation, featuring twelve black and white photographs of Robert Frost and a potted biography of Middlebury College. Includes mailing envelope (Box 1)
  - 20.) Offprint from the Quarterly Journal of Speech: Notes on Frost the Lecturer by Reginald L.Cook. (Cook was a professor of American Literature at Middlebury College and "has served as Director of the Bread Loaf School of English"). (Box 1)
  - 21.) Offprint from the University of Kansas City Review: Winter 1947: Thoreau in Perspectiveby Reginald L Cook (possibly a look at the relationship between Thoreau and Frost) (Box 1)
  - 22.) Offprint from College English, Chicago, IL: Vol 8, No. 5, February 1947: Robert Frost as Teacher by Reginald L Cook. (Box 1)
  - 23.) Offprint from American Literature Vol. XXVIII, No. 1, March, 1956: Froston Frost: The Making of Poems by Reginald L Cook. (Box 1)
  - 24.) Program for A Luncheon in Commemoration of the Ninetieth Anniversary of the Birth of Robert Frost: March 26, 1964 put on by the California Friends of Robert Frost. Laid in are 17 newspaper clippings regarding the death or related issues (wills, legacies, memorials, etc.) for Robert Frost. (Box 1)
  - 25.) Two additional copies of a broadside publicizing a reading by Robert Frost at Stanford University, Monday, May 5th, 1958 at the Memorial Hall, (these copies are not initialed). (Box 1)
  - 26.) 41 misc. newspaper clippings regarding various aspects of the life of Robert Frost including tour dates, books published, society gossip, etc. (Box 1)
  - 27.) 5 misc. magazine articles relating to the various aspects of the Life of Robert Frost. (Box 1)
  - 28.) An application for Admission to the Bread Loaf Writers' Conference (unused) (Box 1)
  - 29.) Offprint from the November 1947 Harper's Magazine: The Easy Chair by Bernard DeVoto which talks about the Bread Loaf writers Conference and the work of Bread Loaf. (Box 1)
  - 30.) An unattributed magazine critique of the Poem Paul's Wife by Robert Frost by Louis Untermeyer, along with a magazine publication (unattributed magazine) of Paul's Wife which includes two woodcut illustrations by James Chapin. (Box 1)
  - 31.) A magazine clipping of a color portrait of Robert Frost by Boris Chaliapin and a clipping featuring the Complete Poems of Robert Frost by Henry Holt And Company (1953) (Box 1)
  - 32.) A page from the Saturday Review of Literature dated Oct. 6,1934 which features the poem Two Tramps in Mud-Time with an accompanying drawing by H. Glintenkamp. (Box 1)
  - 33.) Four copies of The DailyCalifomian: Thursday, May 8,1958 with an article on Robert Frost: "Frost to Keynote University Meeting". (Box 1)
  - 34.) A page from the Christian Science Monitor, March 25,1950 featuring an article: "Only More Sure... Back over the Years" with Robert Frost by Carlyle Morgan. (Box 1)
  - 35.) The Stanford Daily: Monday, May 5,1958 featuring the article: FrostWill Speak Today in Mem Aud Program. (Box 1)
  - 36.) 5 misc. items, either newspaper, magazine or copies relating to the various aspects of Robert Frost (Box 1)
  - 37.) 6 misc. items from the collector -a bag from Holmes Book Co. in San Francisco, two receipts from the Holmes Book Co., two 3x5 cards with notations by the collector and portions of a book cover that mention works by Robert Frost. (Box 1)